AFROKK KHAN

pronounced af • rock

hi@afrokk.dev | LinkedIn.com/in/afrasiyab-k | GitHub.com/Afrokk | www.afrokk.dev

SUMMARY

Full Stack Software Engineering grad with a parallel 7-year tech & creative design industry journey, managing a **1.7M subs YT** channel, former founder of a tech news website, and an avid freelancer with works featured in Forbes, Uber, and more.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: C, Java, Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, SQL (Postgres), HTML/CSS, SASS

Frameworks: React, Node.js, Flask, Vue.js, Next.js, Nuxt, Express, Prisma, Bootstrap, Tailwind

Tools: Git, Docker, REST APIs, CI/CD, Adobe Suite, Figma

EXPERIENCE

Creative Design Manager

March 2019 – Present

YouTube (@xeetechcare)

Remote, Part-time

- Directing a thriving 1.7 million subscribers YouTube channel to produce tech content for a worldwide audience.
- Managing partnerships with top-tier brands including Samsung, Google, Chevrolet, and more across diverse sectors.
- Generating over 5 million monthly views by producing 2,000+ videos on emerging tech, spanning smartphones, computers, electric vehicles, and more.
- Engineered a VueJS channel website and an interactive Discord Python chatbot to boost community engagement.
- Enhanced views from high CPM regions by 40% through SEO strategies, significantly boosting monetization potential.

Lead Teaching Assistant

January 2022 - December 2023

University of Windsor

Windsor, ON

- Mentored 100+ students in four major Computer Science courses including C, OOP with Java and OS Programming.
- Conducted workshops with over 200 students to teach Computer Science tools, including C, Java, SQL, along with multithreading and network socket concepts.

Co-founder

May 2016 – February 2019

GeeksULTD

Remote

- Established and piloted GeeksULTD.COM, a technology/gaming-based website for 3+ years.
- Achieved 2x faster load times by optimizing JavaScript & CSS and integrating CDN technologies like Cloudflare.
- Authored 550+ articles and reviews related to computers, technology, and gaming, reaching 100K+ monthly viewers.
- Partnered with Samsung, Logitech, MSi, and more to publish 30+ product reviews and editorials.

EDUCATION

University of Windsor

Windsor, ON

Bachelors in Computer Science, Minor in Communications, Media & Film | GPA: 3.9/4.0 | President's List

December 2023

PROJECTS (MORE ON AFROKK.DEV)

xeetechcare.com | Vue.js, Nuxt, SSR, Three.js, TypeScript, TailwindCSS, GSAP | GitHub

January 2024

- Pioneered xeetechcare.com, a bespoke server-side rendered website using Nuxt 3 (Vue.js).
- Boosted user time-on-site by 40% through real-time timeline updates, integrating APIs from YouTube, Twitter, Instagram, and TikTok.
- Optimized data fetching pipelines with serverless functions and enhanced UX using Three.js and GSAP animations.

litmus.tools | TypeScript, React, SASS, WebAssembly, JavaScript, Vercel | GitHub

January 2023

- Engineered a comprehensive, **geography-specific** tax calculator and budgeting tool, utilizing **TypeScript**, **WebAssembly**, and **React** in a visually appealing interface.
- Incorporated data from the **US National Bureau of Economic Research** to offer **precise**, **ZIP code-specific** calculations and insights on users' savings and earnings.

HACKATHONS

NASA Space Apps 2023: Won 1st in NASA Space Apps 2023 regional, among 50+ teams, designing a live <u>fire detection system</u>. CS Games 2023: Represented uWindsor in Quebec, implemented cross-platform microservices for security and data sharing.